Now we have a model with movements and a well-dressed costume.
In order to make a more stable animation, we need to make some adjustments to the costume.
Like a belt-like version that is smaller and easier to slide.
In addition to reducing the particle diameter, it can also be used to increase the friction coefficient to prevent sliding.
Using a sewing tool can fix a certain point of the costume on another point.
This function is similar to the fixed to the virtual model.
Using a sewing tool can find the fixed to the virtual model tool.
Using this tool can put the costume on the virtual model, and it will not move because of the action.
The length of the line in the combinator can be controlled by the distance between two points.
In addition, you can also use the sewing tool to fix the two points of the costume and the costume room.
You can also choose the sewing of the line and the line of the costume.
In the costume adjustment, you can start recording the animation.
You can see that due to the fewer stitches in this animation, the motion between the models is relatively large.
For the skirt with a relatively soft fabric and a larger version, there will be a lot of movement.
The movements have been changed, but the fabric is still in the position where the last stitch is.
This will have the feeling that the fabric does not follow the model's body.
For the skirt with a slightly soft fabric, the movement is not so soft that it may cause the model to bend a little.
This is mainly because the speed of one stitch is too fast.
Without fully simulation, it can be applied to the next movement.
Play the animation, and you can see that the fabric itself is very soft and close to the body.
Because the action range of the model is no longer close to the body.
In the case of this, we can see that the movement is the same.
we can change the scene change time and increase the number of action frames
Under this number, the costume simulation will be more stable
Then let's take a look at the comparison
First, change the scene time to the original 1, so that the number of frames is the same as the original
After comparison, you can see that the animation with more frames is more suitable for the real simulation
The physical properties of the material will also affect the animation effect
The internal damping refers to the rebound coefficient of the material
After increasing this value, the material will have resistance, such as in the water, the rebound is slower
Observe the model's waist fold, when the internal damping is relatively high, it looks like there is resistance in the environment
In addition, the density will also significantly affect the simulation effect
The fabric of the skirt itself is polyester, and the density of the polyester fabric is very low
After increasing the density, you can see from the comparison video that when the density becomes larger, the fabric becomes heavier, making it closer to the virtual model
And the fold is more obvious, so it looks like it's softer
In the usual production process, you can adjust the physical properties and compare them to find a more suitable fabric
Thank you for watching
Please like and subscribe to the channel